# **Curriculum Vitae**

#### **Personal Information**

Gábor Forgács

Rudapest, Hungary

forgacsg.github.io

## Summary

I am a problem solver with excellent speaking and writing skills. I am able to work on my own initiative as well as part of a team to achieve the best results possible. I have experience in data analytics with Python and R as well as developing data warehouses and operationalising machine learning models both on-prem and in the cloud (GCP). I am a <u>Google Certified Professional Data Engineer</u>. I also have an interest in web development and I am competent in JavaScript using the MERN stack.

#### **Relevant Skills**

- Python: NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib,
   Scikit-Learn, Flask, Plotly, Dash
- R: dplyr, ggplot2, tidyverse, R Shiny
- Javascript: MERN stack, D3.js
- SQL: T-SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, BQ
- NoSQL: MongoDB
- Docker

- Git, Gitlab CI/CD
- Dashboarding tools: Power BI |
   Tableaum | Qlik
- GIS: Leaflet, QGIS, Spatial Databases (PostGIS)
- Advanced MS Excel
- MS Office (Word, Powerpoint, Visio)

# **Work Experience**

**Data Scientist** | British Telecom ROC.

2022 -

- Built PoC's for validation
- Created and deployed ML models with Python using ScikitLearn & other packages

Senior Data Analyst | British Telecom ROC.

2019 -2022

- Analysed ticket data from various service desk and CRM systems (Pega, Salesforce, SNOW)
- Built and deployed API's for ML models with Flask, Docker and Gitlab CD/CI
- Developed dashboards in Qlik and Python (Dash)

IT Business Analyst (Business Intelligence) | Cushman & Wakefield

2017 - 2019:

- ETL of client data in Python and SQL Server
- Developed dashboards and reports in PowerBI
- Historical Payment Reconciliation in SQL Server for key clients based on generated cash-flow

GÁBOR FORGÁCS forgacsg@gmail.com

### System Analyst | Cushman & Wakefield

2016 - 2017:

- Ensuring data quality for benchmarking
- Reporting user activity trends, benchmarking data pool contents on a quarterly basis
- Project coordination with external developers

## English Language Teacher (part-time) | Tudomány Language School

2012 – 2016: Taught advanced level and business English as a sub-contractor at various companies.

\*References: Ericsson, Ixenit, Bayer, British American Tobacco, Deloitte\*

**Junior Research Fellow** | University of Technology and Economics, 2014 – 2015:

#### **Education**

- Microsoft Professional Program in Data Science 2017 2018
- Graduate student at the Budapest University of Technology and Economics, Dept of History and Philosophy of Science 2011 – 2014
- Master of Arts in Teaching English Language and Literature (University of Pécs) 2009
- Master of Arts in Teaching Philosophy (University of Pécs) 2009

#### **Certificates**

- Google Cloud Certified Professional Data Engineer
- Udemy: The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp
- Coursera: Foundations of Business Strategy
- Coursera: Competitive Strategy
- EdX: Networks, Crowds and Markets
- Coursera: Logic: Language and Information 2

# **Awards, Honours and Memberships**

2009: Second Place at the XXIX. Biannual National Scholarly Competition for Students – in

the category of English Theoretical and Descriptive Linguistics

2008: CEEPUS research scholarship at the Karl Franzens Universität, Graz

2005 – 2009: member of the University of Pécs Kerényi Károly Extracurricular Study Fraternity,

Senior in 2007-2008

## **Language Proficiency**

English
 C2 - Master of Arts in Teaching English Language and Literature (2009)

German B2 TELC intermediate exam, type "C"